<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>K. al-Ajwiba al-ʿArabiyya fī sharḥ al-naṣāʾiḥ al-Yūsufiyya | MIAS Catalogue</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <bibl xml:id="ajwiba">
            <idno type="RG">9</idno>
            <idno type="Alt_RG"/>
            <idno type="RECORDID">339</idno>
            <title xml:lang="ara-Latn-x-lc" type="uniform">K. al-Ajwiba al-ʿArabiyya fī sharḥ al-naṣāʾiḥ al-Yūsufiyya</title>
            <title xml:lang="ara" type="uniform-ara">كتاب الأجوبة العربية في شرح النصائح الوسفية</title>
            <title xml:lang="ara-Latn-x-lc" type="abbreviated">ajwiba</title>
            <title xml:lang="ara-Latn-x-lc" type="full">K. al-Ajwiba al-ʿarabiyya fi sharḥ al-naṣāiḥ al-yūsufiyya</title>
            <title xml:lang="ara-Latn-x-lc" type="alternate">R. al-Yūsufiyya; </title>
            <title xml:lang="eng" type="translationEng"/>
            <author cert="medium" key="person_0001">Ibn al-ʿArabī</author>
            <persName role="att" key="person_0001">Ibn al-ʿArabī</persName>
            <persName role="cwt" key="person_0001">Ibn al-ʿArabī</persName>
            <persName role="ant" key="person_0000">Yūsuf b. Ibrāhīm al-Shāfiʾī</persName>
            <date type="fmEarliestMS" calendar="Hijri-qamari">&lt;700</date>
            <date type="fmDate" calendar="Hijri-qamari"/>
            <placeName type="fmPlace"/>
            <note type="fmComposition"/>
            <date when="1111"
                  cert="high"
                  calendar="Hijri-qamari"
                  evidence="internal">Insert Exact Date of Composition</date>
            <date from="1111"
                  to="1111"
                  cert="medium"
                  calendar="Hijri-qamari"
                  evidence="external">Insert Known Period of Composition</date>
            <date notBefore="1111"
                  notAfter="1111"
                  cert="low"
                  calendar="Hijri-qamari"
                  evidence="conjecture">Insert Conceivable Date Range of Composition</date>
            <incipit type="uniform" xml:lang="ara-Latn-x-lc">al-ḥamdu lillāh alladhī hadānā li-hadhā wa-mā kunā li-nahtadī lawlā an hadānā Allāh laqad jaʿat rusul rabbina bi-l-ḥaqq</incipit>
            <incipit type="uniform-ara" xml:lang="ara">Insert Arabic Incipit</incipit>
            <textLang mainLang="ara">Arabic</textLang>
            <noteGrp type="workDesc">
               <note type="description">Wise sayings, accompanied by explanatory notes. IA says in the introduction that it is a collection of sayings by a certain mystic called ʿAlī al-Kurdī who was ‘smitten with divine love’, and he has appended a commentary on these sayings. Claude Addas adds: “Al-Ajwiba al-‘Arabiyya fî sharh al-nasâ’ih al-Yûsufiyya est une commentaire par Ibn ‘Arabî d’une risâla concernant les devoirs du murîd à l’égard de son shaykh rédigée par Yûsuf b. Ibrâhîm al-Shâfi’î sous l’inspiration de la rûhâniya de ‘Alî al-Kurdî, un “fou” (muwallah ) notoire de Damas (I.A. l’a rencontré, cf.,Fut., II, 522, ed. Bûlaq).”</note>
               <note type="biblioComments">OY lists five mss. of which two, Husein Celebi 447 and Yusuf Aga 4860, although undated, are very early, whilst Yusuf Aga 4860 is from SQ’s library, and is possibly 7th or 8th century. The internal evidence of the text – for example, the language and the mention of his wife – is strong evidence that it is by IA. In addition, the title is listed in one of the lists which IA made of his own works, Fihris muʾallafāt al-shaykh al-akbar (RG142), and it does not seem to be attributed to anyone else. Claude Addas confirms this stating that:: “L’attribution de ce texte à Ibn ‘Arabî ne fait aucun doute ; on y trouve de nombreuses références autobiographiques, par ex, l’investiture de la khirqa par ‘Abd Allâh b. Jâmī”.A number of the poems in this work appear clustered in the Paris Diwan (B.N. 2348) and seemingly nowhere else. Further information on the fully digitized text of RG 9 found in Word format at cb.rayaheen.net/userfiles/download.php?id=1395‎, which extracts as a Word document with name شرح روحانية الشيخ الكردي.doc. The text itself carries a title not listed by Osman Yahia under RG 9, namely: شرح ما نطقت به روحانية سيدي علي الكردي . JC has compared that text to Yusuf Aga 4860 and Husein Celebi 447. The 202 page text in the Word document closely matches the complete text found in Husein Celebi 447 ff.1a-149b. Decapitated Yusuf Aga 4860 p.207 – which we estimate is missing the first 14 pages (7 folios) – starts with the text found at the end of page 11 of the Word document (cf. Husein Celebi f.9a line 2). PDF versions are also available via Google (شرح روحانية الشيخ الكردي لسيدي ابن عربي.pdf).</note>
               <note type="compHist">Insert Revised Composition History</note>
               <note type="structure">Insert Revised Work Structure</note>
               <note type="discussion">Insert Revised Discussion</note>
               <note type="reception">Insert Revised Reception</note>
               <note type="stemmatics">Insert Revised Stemmatics</note>
               <note type="khutba">Insert Transcribed Khutba</note>
            </noteGrp>
            <noteGrp type="references">
               <note type="ijaza">Insert Title of Work as given in Ijāza plus any of IA's comments</note>
               <note type="ijaza_2" resp="Badawī" n=""/>
               <note type="fihris">Insert Title of Work as given in Fihris plus any of IA's comments</note>
               <note type="fihris_2" resp="Awwād" n="191">191</note>
               <note type="fut_mak">Insert mentions of work in fut_mak</note>
               <note type="fut_mak" resp="OY"/>
               <note type="other"/>
            </noteGrp>
            <noteGrp type="mentions">
               <note type="mention">
                  <ref target="#work">Insert target to work(s) mentioned, and can give more detail about precise location as plain text here</ref>
                  <quote xml:lang="ara">Add quotation(s), if relevant</quote>
               </note>
            </noteGrp>
            <noteGrp type="scholarComments">
               <note resp="JC"/>
               <note resp="MC"/>
            </noteGrp>
            <note type="migrationNotes">Related item (non-IA): commentary on risala by ʿAlī al-Kurdī. is it known or unknown? Alternate title: Sharḥ rūḥāniyya al-shaykh al-Kurdī</note>
         </bibl>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
