<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>al-Futūḥāt al-Makkiyya | MIAS Catalogue</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <bibl xml:id="fut_mak">
            <idno type="RG">135</idno>
            <idno type="Alt_RG"/>
            <idno type="RECORDID">11</idno>
            <idno type="Normalized">fut_mak</idno>
            <!-- Titles -->
            <title type="uniform" xml:lang="ara-Latn-x-lc">al-Futūḥāt al-Makkiyya</title>
            <title type="uniform" xml:lang="ara">الفتوحات المكية</title>
            <title type="full" xml:lang="ara-Latn-x-lc">Al-Futūḥāt al- Makkiya fī maʿrifat al-asrār al-mālikiyya wa-l-mulkiyya</title>
            <title type="variant" xml:lang="ara-Latn-x-lc"/>
            <title type="translation" xml:lang="eng">Revelations of Mecca</title>
            <note type="titleNote">Note on Title</note>
            <!-- Textual Identifiers -->
            <incipit type="hamdala" xml:lang="ara-Latn-x-lc">al-ḥamdu lilāh alladhī awjad al-ashiyāʾ ʿan ʿadam wa-ʿadamahu wa-awqaf wajūdahā ʿalā tuwajjah kalimihi li-nataḥaqqaq bidhālik sir ḥudūthhā wa-qidamahā min qidamahi</incipit>
            <incipit type="hamdala" xml:lang="ara">حمدله</incipit>
            <incipit type="muqadimma" xml:lang="ara-Latn-x-lc">Muqadimma</incipit>
            <incipit type="muqadimma" xml:lang="ara">مقدمة</incipit>
            <incipit type="khutba" xml:lang="ara-Latn-x-lc">Khuṭba</incipit>
            <incipit type="khutba" xml:lang="ara">الخطبة بكاملها</incipit>
            <explicit xml:lang="ara-Latn-x-lc">Khiṭām al-naṣṣ</explicit>
            <explicit xml:lang="ara">ختام النص</explicit>
            <note type="textualIdentifiersNote">Note on Textual Identifiers</note>
            <!-- Authorship and Editorial Roles -->
            <author cert="high" key="IA">Ibn al-ʿArabī</author>
            <editor role="role" key="key">Other Roles</editor>
            <persName role="att" key="IA">Ibn al-ʿArabī</persName>
            <note type="verification" subtype="A">Verified A</note>
            <note type="authenticationType" subtype="H">Holograph</note>
            <note type="authenticityNote">Note on Authenticity</note>
            <!-- Composition History -->
            <date type="fmDate" calendar="Hijri-qamari">629/636</date>
            <date type="fmEarliestMS" calendar="Hijri-qamari">636</date>
            <date when="1111" cert="high" calendar="Hijri-qamari">Date of Composition</date>
            <date from="1111" to="1111" cert="medium" calendar="Hijri-qamari">Period of Composition</date>
            <date type="TPQ" notBefore="1111" cert="low" calendar="Hijri-qamari">Earliest</date>
            <date type="TAQ" notAfter="1111" cert="low" calendar="Hijri-qamari">Latest</date>
            <note type="dateNote">Note on Date of Composition</note>
            <placeName type="fmPlace">Damascus</placeName>
            <note type="placeNote">Note on Place of Composition</note>
            <note type="compositionNote"/>
            <!-- Contents -->
            <noteGrp type="workDesc">
               <note type="description">Ibn ʿArabī’s great summary of esoteric knowledge, consisting of 560 chapters and extending to nearly 10,000 pages in the holograph. It totalises all aspects of his work and all the esoteric knowledge of his era. The first recension, completed in Ṣafar 629H, exists only in copies, while the second, written between 632H and 636H, survives in IA’s own hand (see Evkaf Muzesi 1845+). There is still work to be done in distinguishing between the two recensions in the mss base, but considerable progress has been made by Julian Cook and Claude Addas in identifying “markers” which indicate the recension of any given ms. Their research indicates that many later mss. may be hybrids of the two recensions. For details of their work on the two recensions, see ancillary documents.</note>
               <note type="structure">Structure of Work</note>
               <note type="contentsNote">Note on Contents</note>
            </noteGrp>
            <!-- Stemmatics -->
            <note type="stemmatics">Verified by many mss. in both recensions. The best of the second recension is Evkaf Muzesi 1845+ in 37 volumes, which is the original in IA’s hand, written in 636H and carrying over 71 samāʿ.</note>
            <!-- Related Works -->
            <relatedItem type="type" target="#work_id"/>
            <note type="relationsNote">Note on Related Works</note>
            <!-- References to This Work in Other Works -->
            <noteGrp type="references">
               <note type="ijaza" resp="Badawi" n="50">50</note>
               <note type="fihrist" resp="Awwad" n="50">50</note>
               <note type="fut_mak" resp="OY"/>
               <note type="other"/>
               <note type="ijaza" resp="MIAS">
                  <ref target="#ijaza"/>Reference to work in the Ijāza
                </note>
               <note type="fihrist" resp="MIAS">
                  <ref target="#fihrist"/>
                    Reference to work in the Fihrist</note>
               <note type="fut_mak" resp="MIAS">
                  <ref target="#fut_mak"/>
                    References to work in Futūḥāt</note>
               <note type="work">
                  <ref target="#work"/>
                    Referenes to work in other works</note>
            </noteGrp>
            <!-- References in This Work to Other Works -->
            <noteGrp type="mentions">
               <note type="mention">
                  <ref target="#work">Work</ref>
                Reference to other work
                </note>
            </noteGrp>
            <!-- Comments and Corrections -->
            <noteGrp type="scholarComments">
               <note resp="corr."/>
               <note resp="additions_0">RG 135 Al -Fath al-makkî Add La mise à jour de cette rubrique du RG. demandera un certain temps et réclamera le concours de tous les spécialistes. Elle devra, en effet, non seulement signaler les éditions postérieures (à commencer par l'édition critique entreprise par O.Y. lui-même) mais aussi recenser, aussi exhaustivement que possible: 1) les traductions partielles en diverses langues 2) les commentaires (par ex. ceux dont W. Chittick a signalé les mss. dans son article "Notes on Ibn Arabî's influence in the Subcontinent", in The Muslim World, vol. LXXXII, n° 3-4, 1992, pp. 218-241). Que tous ceux qui détiennent des informations propres à enrichir cette rubrique qui est évidemment l'une des plus importantes du R.G. veuillent bien les faire parvenir à Jane Clark.</note>
               <note resp="msAdd.">Later!</note>
               <note resp="JC">
                  <p/>
                  <p/>
               </note>
               <note resp="SH">
                  <p/>
                  <p/>
               </note>
               <note resp="AP">
                  <p/>
                  <p/>
               </note>
            </noteGrp>
            <!-- Migration Notes -->
            <note type="migrationNote">Dates Give two composition dates. Mention date of the vision as well in composition. Chapters/asfār At some stage we may wish to encode some of the chapters that correspond to earlier or other works...</note>
            <!-- Editions, Translations, and Relevant Publications -->
            <noteGrp type="publications">
               <note type="editions">Two critical editions exist. The first, edited by Osman Yahia (Cairo, 1970+) consists of 14 volumes and is incomplete. The second , edited by ʿAbd al-ʿAzīz Sulṭān al-Manṣūb (Yemen, 2011) is in 12 volumes and is complete. It is largely based upon the Konya autograph – the manuscript of the second recension of the book written in 37 sections by Ibn ʿArabī himself – but also takes into account other texts. Critical edition of the poems on the letters in chapter 2 by Maurizio Marconi in Azufre Rojo vo. 7 (2020).</note>
               <note type="translations">There is as yet no complete translation of the Futūḥāt. Eric Winkel is working on one, and information on how to access his translation can be found on http://www.ibnarabisociety.org/infopdf/futuhat-winkel-announcement.pdf. and https://www.createspace.com/pub/simplesitesearch.search.do?sitesearch_query=Eric+A.+Winkel&amp;sitesearch_type=STORE. In addition, there are very many partial translations. The following list includes only a few of the more substantial ones. English Eric Winkel, The Openings Revealed at Mecca (New York, 2018– ) William Chittick The Sufi Path of Knowledge, New York, 1981. (Substantial sections of translation from many chapters) William Chittick, The Self-Disclosure of God, New York, 1998. (Substantial sections of translation from many chapters) James W Morris: ‘How to study the Futūḥāt; Ibn ʿArabī’s own advice’ in Muhyiddin Ibn ʿArabī (1165-1240), Oxford, 1993 (Introduction) William Chittick: ‘Two chapters from the Futūḥāt ’ in Muhyiddin Ibn ʿArabī (1165-1240), Oxford, 1993 (Chapters 317 and 339) William Chittick: Imaginal Worlds, New York, 1994 (Chapter 66) Eric Winkel: Mysteries of Purity, Indiana, 1995 (Chapter 68) Michel Chodkiewicz, William Chittick, James W Morris, Denis Gril: The Meccan Revelations,Vols 1 &amp; 2 New York, 2002, 2004 (Selections from 19 chapters, based upon the French edition of 1988) Aisha Bewley: The Mysteries of Bearing Witness, Chicago, 2002 (Selections from 1, 50, 67, 560) Gracia Lopez Anguita: ‘On the Inner Knowledge of Spirits Made of an Igneous Mixture: Chapter 9 of Futūḥāt al-Makkiyya’, JMIAS, 44, 2008 pp. 1-24 Aisha Bewley: Ibn ʿArabī on the Mysteries of the Purifying Alms, no place, 2009. ( Chaper 70) Aisha Bewley: Ibn ʿArabī on the Mysteries of the Pilgrimage, no place, 2009. (Chapter 72) Stephen Hirtenstein, The Alchemy of Human Happiness, Oxford 2017 (chapter 167) French Stephane Ruspoli:L’Alchimie du Bonheur Parfait, Paris, 1981. (Chapter 167) Charles-André Gilis: Le Coran et la fonction d’Hermès, Paris 1984 (Section 10 of Chapter 198), republished in 1998 under the title: Les Trente-six Attestations Coraniques de l’Unité. Maurice Gloton: Traité de l’Amour, Paris, 1986. (Chapter 178 on love) Michel Chodkiewicz, William Chittick, James W Morris, Denis Gril: Les Illuminations de la Mecque, Paris, 1988. (Selections from 19 chapters) Charles-André Gilis: Textes sur le Jeüne, Beirut, 1998. (Chapter 71) Charles-André Gilis: Le prière du jour du vendredi, Paris, 1994. (Chaper 69) Moreno Giannini: Le Voyage Spirituel, Louvain-la-Neuve, 1995. (Chapter 367) Michel Valsan: ‘al-Futūḥāt al-Makkiyyah: Chapter 172 on the Knowledge of the Station of Tawḥīd’, Science Sacrée, 7, 2005. pp. 46-58. (First part only). A Penot: Les Révelations de la Mecque, Paris, 2009. (Partial translations of Chapters 1-55 on cosmology) Maurice Gloton: De la mort à la résurrection : chapitres 61 à 65 des Ouvertures spirituelles mekkoises, Beirut 2009; Paris 2009. Italian ʿAbdul-Hadi Agueli, “El-Akbariya”, Il Convito, Cairo (Egypt), 1907, pp. 48-50 (Chapter 401) Massimo Jevolella, L’alchimia della felicità, Como, 1996 (Chapter 167) Placido Fontanesi “Prologo del libro”, Rivista di studi tradizionali, 1997, (Khutbah) Placido Fontanesi, “Introduzione”, Rivista di studi tradizionali, 1998, pp. 22-56 (First part of Introduction) Placido Fontanesi, “La conoscenza degli uomini dello sconcerto”, Rivista di studi tradizionali, 1980, pp. 71-85 (Chapter 50) Placido Fontanesi, “La conoscenza dei pensieri satanici che affiorano alla coscienza”, Rivista di studi tradizionali, 1983, pp. 17-32 (Chapter 55) Placido Fontanesi, “Il pentimento” Rivista di studi tradizionali, 2003, pp. 205-231 (Chapter 74) Placido Fontanesi, “Lo scrupolo ed i suoi segreti”, Rivista di studi tradizionali, 1986, pp. 142-153 (Chapter 91) Placido Fontanesi, “La conoscenza della stazione spirituale dell’abbandono dello scrupolo”, Rivista di studi tradizionali, 1986, pp. 154-158 (Chapter 92) Placido Fontanesi, “La conoscenza della povertà e dei suoi segreti”, Rivista di studi tradizionali, 1985, pp. 11-22 (Chapter 162) Placido Fontanesi, “La conoscenza della volontà”, Rivista di studi tradizionali, 1986, pp. 82-97 (Chapter 226) Placido Fontanesi, “La conoscenza della nafs”, Rivista di studi tradizionali, 1984, pp. 7-16 (Chapter 267) Maurizio Marconi, ‘Testi deel al-Futuhat al-Makkiyya’, Azufre Rojo 7 (2020) Maurizio Marconi, ‘Capitolo 2 di al-Futuhat al-Makkiyya’ in Azufre Rojo vol. 10 (2022)</note>
               <note type="translationsEur">German Wolfgang Herrman: Abhandlung Ẓber die Liebe, Zurich, 2009 (Chapter 178).</note>
               <note type="additions_1">Add La mise à jour de cette rubrique du RG. demandera un certain temps et réclamera le concours de tous les spécialistes. Elle devra, en effet, non seulement signaler les éditions postérieures (à commencer par l'édition critique entreprise par O.Y. lui-même) mais aussi recenser, aussi exhaustivement que possible: 1) les traductions partielles en diverses langues 2) les commentaires (par ex. ceux dont W. Chittick a signalé les mss. dans son article "Notes on Ibn Arabî's influence in the Subcontinent", in The Muslim World, vol. LXXXII, n° 3-4, 1992, pp. 218-241). (MC)</note>
               <note type="additions_2"/>
               <note type="additions_3"/>
            </noteGrp>
            <!-- Administrative Notes -->
            <noteGrp type="admin">
               <note type="archive">y</note>
               <note type="library">Y</note>
            </noteGrp>
            <textLang mainLang="ara">Arabic</textLang>
            <!-- End -->
         </bibl>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
